<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steinitz Chess Club</title>
    <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Steinitz Chess Club</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024 Steinitz Festival</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2024-05-11_steinitz-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2024-05-11_steinitz-festival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a family affair&amp;hellip; The 47th anniversary Steinitz Chess Festival.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 CTCF Club League</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2025-ctcf-club-league/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2025-ctcf-club-league/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2025 CTCF Club League is Cape Town’s premier team chess competition, bringing together the region’s strongest clubs in an 11-round tournament played over three months. The league showcases both established masters and rising talents, fostering competitive spirit and community among local players. With the season still underway, every round remains crucial as teams battle for top honors and bragging rights in one of South Africa’s most prestigious club events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate before you Calculate!</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/blog/evaluate-before-you-calculate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/blog/evaluate-before-you-calculate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;positional-insight-the-four-key-elements&#34;&gt;Positional Insight: The Four Key Elements&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Positional insight is gained by applying four key elements to any position. These universal elements will improve your calculation process once fully grasped. Don’t rush to calculate lines—first aim to understand the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the 2019 Cape Town Club League</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/blog/reflections-on-2019-chess-western-province-league/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/blog/reflections-on-2019-chess-western-province-league/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;reflections-on-steinitz-in-the-wp-league&#34;&gt;Reflections on Steinitz in the WP League&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I look back at the 2019 Western Province League, I feel immense pride in what Steinitz Chess Club has achieved. Over the course of that season, we played &lt;strong&gt;11 matches&lt;/strong&gt;, winning &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; and drawing just one — against a strong MRL side. Not once did we taste defeat. That kind of consistency doesn’t happen by accident. It reflects years of teamwork, preparation, and commitment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2014 AfriClub Champs</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2014-african-club-championship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2014-african-club-championship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In March 2014, Cape Town proudly hosted the prestigious African Club Chess Championship at the Sun Hotel. The event brought together top club teams from across the continent, showcasing Africa’s finest chess talent in a spirit of competition and camaraderie. Players battled over the boards in a festival of strategy and skill, while the Mother City provided a fitting backdrop with its vibrant culture and iconic scenery. The tournament not only highlighted the growing strength of African chess but also reinforced Cape Town’s reputation as a hub for international sporting events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Talmarkes</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/andrew-talmarkes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/andrew-talmarkes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew Talmarkes is an accomplished chess coach, FIDE-licensed arbiter, and long-time leader within Cape Town’s Steinitz Chess Club. He is the Director of the Insight Chess Academy, providing specialized individual and group coaching—including tailored sessions for clients with ADHD or focus challenges.&#xA;A pillar in chess administration, he has served in numerous key roles: tournament director, deputy chief arbiter at the 2024 Cape Town Masters Challenge, and fixture within the CHESSA arbiter program as well as the Western Province youth coaching scene.&#xA;Awarded the Community Builder Award in 2013 for his work on Mitchell’s Plain Chess Development and Library Project, Talmarkes continues to shape youth and community chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clinton Solomon</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/clinton-solomon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/clinton-solomon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am primarily a chess parent of a talented youth player. I enjoy being able to help the other young players in my capacity as a club youth director.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colin Webber</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/colin-webber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/colin-webber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Colin Webber is a former a chess parent (his son Ethan no longer plays competitively), now an &amp;ldquo;adult improver&amp;rdquo; player who enjoys supporting up-and-coming young players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Declan Platen</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/declan-platen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/declan-platen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Declan Platen is the youngest member of Steinitz Exco but is one of the most impactful in his role as Club Captain. During the 2025 CTCF league he managed the placement of players in all club teams while also producing an outstanding performance in the B and A teams. As of 2025, he holds a FIDE rating of 1732 in standard chess and 1753 in rapid formats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elements</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/elements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;table-of-content &#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;summary&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;      Table of Contents&#xA;    &#xA;  &lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#heading-2&#34;&gt;Heading 2&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;      &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#heading-3&#34;&gt;Heading 3&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#heading-4&#34;&gt;Heading 4&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;              &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#heading-5&#34;&gt;Heading 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;              &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;          &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#emphasis&#34;&gt;Emphasis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#button&#34;&gt;Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#link&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#paragraph&#34;&gt;Paragraph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ordered-list&#34;&gt;Ordered List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#unordered-list&#34;&gt;Unordered List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#notice&#34;&gt;Notice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tab&#34;&gt;Tab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#accordions&#34;&gt;Accordions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#code-and-syntax-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code and Syntax Highlighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#blockquote&#34;&gt;Blockquote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tables&#34;&gt;Tables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#image&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#gallery&#34;&gt;Gallery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#slider&#34;&gt;Slider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#youtube-video&#34;&gt;Youtube video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#custom-video&#34;&gt;Custom video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/nav&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of headings. You can use this heading by the following markdown rules. For example: use &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; for heading 1 and use &lt;code&gt;######&lt;/code&gt; for heading 6.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenny Willenberg</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/kenneth-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/kenneth-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Sean “Kenny” Willenberg is a South African Candidate Master (CM), currently regarded as one of Cape Town’s stronger players, with a classical rating hovering near 1927.&#xA;A product of the Western Cape chess scene and Head Coach of Steinitz Chess Club, Kenny has demonstrated consistent tournament performance both in national closed championships and local league play&#xA;Once the SA Under-20 Champion, he has also completed multiple appearances in the SA Closed Championship, establishing himself early as a top junior in the country. Beyond the board, he has contributed as a chess coach through programs such as at Curro Schools, nurturing new talent in South Africa.&#xA;Overall, Kenny embodies a blend of competitive strength and mentorship, making him a respected figure in the South African chess community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lyndon Bouah</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/lyndon-bouah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/lyndon-bouah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Lyndon Bouah is a distinguished figure in South African chess—both as a competitive veteran and as a scholar-administrator. Holding the title of Candidate Master, he has represented his nation at events including the 1992 and 1994 Chess Olympiads. In 2024, Bouah made a remarkable return to competitive play, emerging as co-champion in the Senior Section of the South African Closed Chess Championship, achieving an undefeated 8.5/11 alongside Dr. Shabier Bhawoodien.&#xA;Off the board, Dr. Bouah is a committed researcher and author, notably publishing Reflection on Chess in the Rainbow Nation, a deeply personal and cultural exploration of chess in South Africa. He also serves as the Chief Director for Sport and Recreation in the Western Cape, blending his passion for chess with leadership in public service.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mark Lewis</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/mark-lewis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/mark-lewis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Lewis is a seasoned chess coach and a founding member of Cape Town’s Steinitz Chess Club, established in 1976 when four high-school students in Bonteheuwel came together to form a club named after World Champion Wilhelm Steinitz.&#xA;A respected leader in South African chess, Lewis is a former president of both the Steinitz Chess Club and the Cape Town Chess Federation (CTCF). Under his leadership, Steinitz grew into one of the strongest clubs in the country, winning national titles and nurturing top players from the Cape Flats.&#xA;In addition to his administrative and coaching roles, Lewis remains active as a competitive player, highlighted by his victory at the 2022 South African Senior Championship, scoring 7.5 points. His lifelong dedication has left a lasting mark on South African chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At &lt;strong&gt;Steinitz Chess Club&lt;/strong&gt;, we’re not just about chess — we’re about people. That means we respect your privacy and take care to protect any personal information you share with us. This policy explains, in plain language, what we collect, why we collect it, and how you stay in control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ready to build your next project with Hugo?</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland Willenberg</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/roland-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/roland-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Roland Willenberg is a veteran South African chess coach and one of the founding members of Steinitz. As a trailblazer in coaching, he was recognized as Cape Town’s first professional chess coach.&#xA;Roland is also known as the father and early mentor of his sons, Kenny and Craig, both former junior South African champions. His contributions to South African chess—through community building, mentorship, and fostering talent—cement his reputation as a key figure in nurturing chess culture on the Cape Flats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shaun Willenberg</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/shaun-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/shaun-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shaun Willenberg is a founding member of the Steinitz Chess Club in Cape Town, established in 1976. The club was formed by four high-school students in the Kalksteensfontein area of Bonteheuwel, who named it after the first recognised chess world champion, Austrian Wilhelm Steinitz.&#xA;Shaun has been actively involved in the club&amp;rsquo;s activities over the years. In the 2020 Steinitz Chess Festival, he was among the top performers, finishing on tiebreak in a five-way tie for first place.&#xA;Shaun&amp;rsquo;s contributions have been instrumental in the club&amp;rsquo;s development and success, reflecting his dedication to promoting chess in the Cape Flats community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What people Are Saying About Steinitz Chess Club</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
