<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steinitz Chess Club - With Unity to Prosperity</title>
    <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Steinitz Chess Club - With Unity to Prosperity</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025 CTCF Club League</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2025_ctcf-club-league/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2025_ctcf-club-league/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2025 CTCF Club League is Cape Town’s premier team chess competition, bringing together the region’s strongest clubs in an 11-round tournament played over three months. The league showcases both established masters and rising talents, fostering competitive spirit and community among local players. With the season still underway, every round remains crucial as teams battle for top honors and bragging rights in one of South Africa’s most prestigious club events.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;notice-head&#34;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34; width=&#34;22&#34; height=&#34;22&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;path stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; d=&#34;m16.862 4.487 1.687-1.688a1.875 1.875 0 1 1 2.652 2.652L6.832 19.82a4.5 4.5 0 0 1-1.897 1.13l-2.685.8.8-2.685a4.5 4.5 0 0 1 1.13-1.897L16.863 4.487Zm0 0L19.5 7.125&#34; /&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Hermanus Chess Club Open</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2025_hermanus-chess-club-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2025_hermanus-chess-club-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hermanus Chess Club hosted it&amp;rsquo;s annual open on a rainy April day. However, multiple Steinitz players shone brightly, bringing home medals and trophies in all divisions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate before you Calculate!</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/blog/evaluate-before-you-calculate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/blog/evaluate-before-you-calculate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;positional-insight-the-four-key-elements&#34;&gt;Positional Insight: The Four Key Elements&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Positional insight is gained by applying four key elements to any position. These universal elements will improve your calculation process once fully grasped. Don’t rush to calculate lines—first aim to understand the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Steinitz Festival</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2024_steinitz-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2024_steinitz-festival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 47th anniversary Steinitz Chess Festival took place at Fairbairn College, Goodwood. 250 players participated with various Junior age groups, rapid sections, Fide rated sections. Players came from as far afield as Namibia, KZN and Mossel Bay, Overberg.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Club Championship</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2024-04-13_steinitz-club-championship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2024-04-13_steinitz-club-championship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2024 Annual Steinitz Chess Club Championship took place in Cape Town on Saturday, April 13th, 2024. The event featured six rounds played at a rapid time control of 20 minutes plus a 5-second increment per move. Bringing together a strong field of club members, the championship provided an exciting day of competitive chess, highlighting both seasoned players and rising stars within the Steinitz community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 SA Senior Closed</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2024_sa-senior-closed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2024_sa-senior-closed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2024 SA Senior Closed at the iconic Newlands venue was a fiercely contested and well-organized event, ending with Dr Lyndon Bouah and FM Shabier Bhawoodien sharing the senior title in a fitting display of competitive balance and sporting tradition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 CTCF Club League</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2022_ctcf-club-league/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2022_ctcf-club-league/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to our Steinitz A-team for winning the Premier Division of the 2022 Chess WP Club League Championship! We also congratulate Kraaifontein (winners of B Division), Capablanca (winners of C Division) and Delft (winners of D Division).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the 2019 Cape Town Club League</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/blog/reflections-on-2019-chess-western-province-league/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/blog/reflections-on-2019-chess-western-province-league/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;reflections-on-steinitz-in-the-wp-league&#34;&gt;Reflections on Steinitz in the WP League&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I look back at the 2019 Western Province League, I feel immense pride in what Steinitz Chess Club has achieved. Over the course of that season, we played &lt;strong&gt;11 matches&lt;/strong&gt;, winning &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; and drawing just one — against a strong MRL side. Not once did we taste defeat. That kind of consistency doesn’t happen by accident. It reflects years of teamwork, preparation, and commitment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2014 AfriClub Champs</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2014_african-club-championship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/gallery/2014_african-club-championship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In March 2014, Cape Town proudly hosted the prestigious African Club Chess Championship at the Sun Hotel. The event brought together top club teams from across the continent, showcasing Africa’s finest chess talent in a spirit of competition and camaraderie. Players battled over the boards in a festival of strategy and skill, while the Mother City provided a fitting backdrop with its vibrant culture and iconic scenery. The tournament not only highlighted the growing strength of African chess but also reinforced Cape Town’s reputation as a hub for international sporting events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Akemdien</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/alex-akemdien/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/alex-akemdien/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alex Akemdien is a rising talent in the chess world, known for his sharp tactical vision and calm approach under pressure. He began playing chess at a young age and quickly distinguished himself on the local circuit, earning recognition for his rapid improvement and consistent performances against seasoned opponents. Over the years, Alex has represented his club in multiple regional and national tournaments, where he has delivered notable results on top boards. His ability to combine creative attacking play with solid strategic understanding has made him a formidable competitor. Beyond individual accolades, Alex has contributed significantly to his team’s success, helping secure podium finishes in league competitions. Dedicated to continual growth, he studies classical games and modern opening theory with equal enthusiasm, ensuring his style remains both dynamic and adaptable. With his ambition and discipline, Alex Akemdien is steadily building a reputation as one of the promising chess players to watch in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Talmarkes </title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/andrew-talmarkes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/andrew-talmarkes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew Talmarkes is an accomplished chess coach, FIDE-licensed arbiter, and long-time leader within Cape Town’s Steinitz Chess Club. He is the Director of the Insight Chess Academy, providing specialized individual and group coaching—including tailored sessions for clients with ADHD or focus challenges.&#xA;A pillar in chess administration, he has served in numerous key roles: tournament director, deputy chief arbiter at the 2024 Cape Town Masters Challenge, and fixture within the CHESSA arbiter program as well as the Western Province youth coaching scene.&#xA;Awarded the Community Builder Award in 2013 for his work on Mitchell’s Plain Chess Development and Library Project, Talmarkes continues to shape youth and community chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Talmarkes </title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/andrew-talmarkes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/andrew-talmarkes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew Talmarkes is an accomplished chess coach, FIDE-licensed arbiter, and long-time leader within Cape Town’s Steinitz Chess Club. He is the Director of the Insight Chess Academy, providing specialized individual and group coaching—including tailored sessions for clients with ADHD or focus challenges.&#xA;A pillar in chess administration, he has served in numerous key roles: tournament director, deputy chief arbiter at the 2024 Cape Town Masters Challenge, and fixture within the CHESSA arbiter program as well as the Western Province youth coaching scene.&#xA;Awarded the Community Builder Award in 2013 for his work on Mitchell’s Plain Chess Development and Library Project, Talmarkes continues to shape youth and community chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Talmarkes </title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/andrew-talmarkes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/andrew-talmarkes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew Talmarkes is an accomplished chess coach, FIDE-licensed arbiter, and long-time leader within Cape Town’s Steinitz Chess Club. He is the Director of the Insight Chess Academy, providing specialized individual and group coaching—including tailored sessions for clients with ADHD or focus challenges.&#xA;A pillar in chess administration, he has served in numerous key roles: tournament director, deputy chief arbiter at the 2024 Cape Town Masters Challenge, and fixture within the CHESSA arbiter program as well as the Western Province youth coaching scene.&#xA;Awarded the Community Builder Award in 2013 for his work on Mitchell’s Plain Chess Development and Library Project, Talmarkes continues to shape youth and community chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benjamin Dubbeld</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/benjamin-dubbeld/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/benjamin-dubbeld/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Dubbeld is a promising young chess player from Cape Town. Introduced to competitive chess in grade 8 at Westerford High School in 2023, he quickly developed a love for the game and began participating in local tournaments in 2024.&#xA;Now in grade 10, Benjamin is a key member of his school&amp;rsquo;s first team, contributing to their successes in interschool competitions. His strong performances have earned him selection for the Western Province Under-18 team, which will compete in Gqeberha in December.&#xA;Benjamin combines a strategic approach with keen tactical awareness, showing steady growth as he gains experience in both school and regional competitions. He is widely regarded as one of the rising talents in Western Province chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bernard Dubbeld</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/bernard-dubbeld/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/bernard-dubbeld/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bernard Dubbeld is a South African chess player who returned to competitive play in 2024, taking part in several tournaments in Cape Town and contributing actively in the local club league.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Callum Lau</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/callum-lau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/callum-lau/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Callum Lau is an emerging talent in Cape Town and active member of Steinitz Chess Club.&#xA;In 2025 Callum achieved 3rd Place in the Western Cape Schools Chess High School Individual Provincial Championship, Representing Rondebosch Boys&amp;rsquo; High School.&#xA;His outstanding performance among the province&amp;rsquo;s top young chess talents earned him a coveted spot at the National Championships, where he will represent the Western Cape at the highest level of school chess competition in South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clinton Solomon</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/clinton-solomon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/clinton-solomon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clinton Solomon is a passionate chess organizer, mentor, and advocate for youth chess in Cape Town. As the Youth Director of Steinitz Chess Club, he works tirelessly to create opportunities for young players, providing access to quality coaching, structured tournaments, and a supportive community. Since 2019, Clinton has traveled extensively across South Africa with his son, Izaiah Solomon—one of the region’s most promising young chess talents—attending both Federation and school chess tournaments. These experiences have given him a deep understanding of the needs and challenges facing youth chess players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clinton Solomon</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/clinton-solomon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/clinton-solomon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clinton Solomon is a passionate chess organizer, mentor, and advocate for youth chess in Cape Town. As the Youth Director of Steinitz Chess Club, he works tirelessly to create opportunities for young players, providing access to quality coaching, structured tournaments, and a supportive community. Since 2019, Clinton has traveled extensively across South Africa with his son, Izaiah Solomon—one of the region’s most promising young chess talents—attending both Federation and school chess tournaments. These experiences have given him a deep understanding of the needs and challenges facing youth chess players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colin Webber</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/colin-webber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/colin-webber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Colin Webber is an active member of the Cape Town chess community, balancing his own journey as an “adult improver” with his passion for supporting the game. A former chess parent—his son Ethan no longer plays competitively—Colin has stayed deeply connected to the sport through both playing and service. He currently serves as the Technical Officer and Webmaster of Steinitz Chess Club, where he helps manage the club’s digital presence and supports its ongoing growth. Alongside his technical contributions, Colin enjoys encouraging and mentoring young players, drawing on his experiences as both a parent and competitor. His enthusiasm for lifelong learning and his commitment to fostering talent make him a valuable part of the Steinitz family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colin Webber</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/colin-webber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/colin-webber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Colin Webber is an active member of the Cape Town chess community, balancing his own journey as an “adult improver” with his passion for supporting the game. A former chess parent—his son Ethan no longer plays competitively—Colin has stayed deeply connected to the sport through both playing and service. He currently serves as the Technical Officer and Webmaster of Steinitz Chess Club, where he helps manage the club’s digital presence and supports its ongoing growth. Alongside his technical contributions, Colin enjoys encouraging and mentoring young players, drawing on his experiences as both a parent and competitor. His enthusiasm for lifelong learning and his commitment to fostering talent make him a valuable part of the Steinitz family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curtis Gal</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/curtis-gal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/curtis-gal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Curtis Gal discovered chess in primary school and quickly developed a passion for the game. He dreams of one day becoming a Grandmaster and is working hard to achieve this goal in the shortest possible time. One of his proudest achievements so far has been representing the West Coast region.&#xA;In 2024, Curtis chose Steinitz as his first club, drawn by its strong reputation and sense of camaraderie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Declan Platen</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/declan-platen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/declan-platen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Declan Platen is a respected player, coach, and leader within the Steinitz Chess Club, where he currently serves as Club Captain. Known for his steady play and deep understanding of the game, Declan has represented Steinitz in league competitions and other events, contributing both on and off the board. As a coach, he is dedicated to nurturing young talent, sharing his knowledge and experience to help players sharpen their skills and build confidence. His approachable teaching style and passion for chess make him a role model for many up-and-coming players in the Western Cape. In his role as Club Captain, Declan fosters team spirit and ensures that Steinitz continues its proud tradition of excellence and camaraderie. Balancing competitive play with mentorship, he exemplifies the values of leadership, sportsmanship, and commitment to the growth of chess in his community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Declan Platen</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/declan-platen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/declan-platen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Declan Platen is a respected player, coach, and leader within the Steinitz Chess Club, where he currently serves as Club Captain. Known for his steady play and deep understanding of the game, Declan has represented Steinitz in league competitions and other events, contributing both on and off the board. As a coach, he is dedicated to nurturing young talent, sharing his knowledge and experience to help players sharpen their skills and build confidence. His approachable teaching style and passion for chess make him a role model for many up-and-coming players in the Western Cape. In his role as Club Captain, Declan fosters team spirit and ensures that Steinitz continues its proud tradition of excellence and camaraderie. Balancing competitive play with mentorship, he exemplifies the values of leadership, sportsmanship, and commitment to the growth of chess in his community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donovan Allies</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/donovan-allies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/donovan-allies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Donovan Allies is a committed and longstanding figure in Cape Town’s chess community, known for both his playing strength and his dedication to the development of the game. Over the years, he has competed in numerous league and open tournaments, consistently bringing determination and fighting spirit to the board. Donovan has represented his club with distinction, contributing to team successes in the fiercely competitive Western Province Chess League. Beyond his individual play, he is admired for his sportsmanship and his willingness to share knowledge and inspire others—particularly younger players making their way in the chess world. His passion for chess extends beyond competition, as he actively supports initiatives that promote the game at grassroots level. Through his steady presence and commitment, Donovan Allies continues to embody the values of discipline, resilience, and community that define the best of South African chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elements</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/elements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;table-of-content &#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;summary&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;      Table of Contents&#xA;    &#xA;  &lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#heading-2&#34;&gt;Heading 2&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;      &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#heading-3&#34;&gt;Heading 3&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#heading-4&#34;&gt;Heading 4&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;              &lt;ol&gt;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#heading-5&#34;&gt;Heading 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;              &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;          &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#emphasis&#34;&gt;Emphasis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#button&#34;&gt;Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#link&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#paragraph&#34;&gt;Paragraph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ordered-list&#34;&gt;Ordered List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#unordered-list&#34;&gt;Unordered List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#notice&#34;&gt;Notice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tab&#34;&gt;Tab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#accordions&#34;&gt;Accordions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#code-and-syntax-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code and Syntax Highlighting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#blockquote&#34;&gt;Blockquote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tables&#34;&gt;Tables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#image&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#gallery&#34;&gt;Gallery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#slider&#34;&gt;Slider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#youtube-video&#34;&gt;Youtube video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#custom-video&#34;&gt;Custom video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/nav&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of headings. You can use this heading by the following markdown rules. For example: use &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; for heading 1 and use &lt;code&gt;######&lt;/code&gt; for heading 6.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethan Samuels</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/ethan-samuels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/ethan-samuels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ethan Samuels is an accomplished young adult chess player and coach from Cape Town, South Africa. Known for his sharp tactical awareness and steady positional play, he has developed a strong reputation both over the board and as a mentor to aspiring players. Ethan has represented his club and province in numerous competitions, consistently achieving notable results and establishing himself as one of the promising young figures in the South African chess scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethan Samuels</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/ethan-samuels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/ethan-samuels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ethan Samuels is an accomplished young adult chess player and coach from Cape Town, South Africa. Known for his sharp tactical awareness and steady positional play, he has developed a strong reputation both over the board and as a mentor to aspiring players. Ethan has represented his club and province in numerous competitions, consistently achieving notable results and establishing himself as one of the promising young figures in the South African chess scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Furqaan Bowman</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/furqaan-bowman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/furqaan-bowman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Furqaan Bowman is a dedicated youth chess player whose journey reflects both talent and resilience. His strongest performance came during the Junior League U16, where he achieved a tournament performance rating of 1630 — a clear sign of his ability to compete at a high level when focused and motivated.&#xA;Like many young players, Furqaan has taken time away from the board, but his passion for the game remains undimmed. He enjoys the challenge chess brings, testing his creativity, focus, and problem-solving under pressure. Known for his calm presence and thoughtful approach to the game, Furqaan brings a maturity to the board that belies his years.&#xA;As he continues his chess journey, Furqaan is looking to build on past achievements and rediscover his competitive rhythm. His return to active play signals not only unfinished business but also the promise of future growth in the sport he loves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glenn Willenberg</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/glenn-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/glenn-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Glen I. Willenberg is a seasoned chess player and life-long member of Steinitz Chess Club.&#xA;Throughout his chess career, Glen has participated in various tournaments, including the South African Closed Chess Championship 2024, where he competed in the Seniors category .&#xA;Beyond individual competitions, Glen is actively involved in the chess community. As of 2025 he proudly represents his club A-team at the CTCF club league.&#xA;Glen&amp;rsquo;s dedication to chess and his active participation in both competitive and community events highlight his commitment to the game and its development in South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Izaiah Solomon</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/izaiah-solomon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/izaiah-solomon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Izaiah Solomon is a talented young chess player from South Africa, currently a Grade 10 learner at Curro Somerset West. He has demonstrated exceptional skill and leadership in the chess community.&#xA;Achievements:&#xA;Provincial Representation: In September 2025, Izaiah was selected to represent the Western Cape Boys Under-18 team at the Mzansi Interprovincial Youth Chess Championships (MIYCC), showcasing his prowess at the provincial level.&#xA;Club Championship Success: In 2024, as a Grade 9 learner, Izaiah earned a silver medal at the Western Cape Club Championship, highlighting his competitive edge in regional tournaments.&#xA;Team Leadership: Serving as captain, Izaiah led the Steinitz Chess Club&amp;rsquo;s Under-18 team to victory in the Cape Town Junior Chess League&amp;rsquo;s A Division in 2024, underscoring his leadership and teamwork abilities.&#xA;Regional Championship Victory: In 2025, he won the inaugural Overberg Schools Chess Championship (OSAJCCC), demonstrating his dominance in regional competitions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesse Palmer</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/jesse-palmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/jesse-palmer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jesse Palmer is a promising young chess talent from Cape Town, South Africa. He holds the title of Arena International Master (AIM) and has achieved impressive FIDE ratings across all formats.&#xA;Since 2024 he has since demonstrated remarkable improvement. He has participated in numerous tournaments, consistently achieving strong results. For instance, in the 2025 Bellville Rapid Tournament, he scored 6 points out of 6, showcasing his dominance in the rapid format.&#xA;Beyond his individual accomplishments, Jesse is an active member of the chess community. He has represented his school, Curro Durbanville, in various competitions, contributing to their success. His dedication to the game and rapid progression have made him a notable figure among his peers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jody Roman</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/jody-roman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/jody-roman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jody Roman has always had a passion for chess. Through a chance interaction with one of Steinitz’s long-standing members, he was reintroduced to the game and welcomed into the close-knit Steinitz family. As a social player and adult improver, Jody has been eager to contribute—taking on the role of Team Captain for various development teams, competing more actively in local tournaments, and even stepping into an ExCo position at the club.&#xA;Reflecting on his journey, Jody lives by the words of Wilhelm Steinitz: “Chess is not for timid souls.” The game brings both highs and lows, but for him, it is about taking the bull by the horns and enjoying the ride.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jody Roman</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/jody-roman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/jody-roman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jody Roman has always had a passion for chess. Through a chance interaction with one of Steinitz’s long-standing members, he was reintroduced to the game and welcomed into the close-knit Steinitz family. As a social player and adult improver, Jody has been eager to contribute—taking on the role of Team Captain for various development teams, competing more actively in local tournaments, and even stepping into an ExCo position at the club.&#xA;Reflecting on his journey, Jody lives by the words of Wilhelm Steinitz: “Chess is not for timid souls.” The game brings both highs and lows, but for him, it is about taking the bull by the horns and enjoying the ride.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Adriaanse</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/jordan-adriaanse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/jordan-adriaanse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jordan Adriaanse is a dedicated youth chess player and an active member of the Steinitz Chess Club. He has distinguished himself through both provincial representation and consistent club participation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenneth Willenberg</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/kenneth-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/kenneth-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Sean “Kenny” Willenberg is a South African Candidate Master (CM), currently regarded as one of the country’s strongest players. A product of Steinitz Chess Club and the proud Willenberg chess-playing legacy, Kenny has built a reputation for consistent success in both national closed championships and local league competitions. Once crowned South African Under-20 Champion, he has made multiple appearances at the SA Closed Championship, firmly establishing himself as one of the nation’s leading players early in his career.&#xA;Beyond his own competitive achievements, Kenny has dedicated himself to coaching and talent development, working through programs at Curro Durbanville and Reddam House Durbanville. His impact as a coach was most prominently seen at the 2025 Top Schools competition, where his Reddam U9 team not only placed first in their division but also swept all six board prizes—a rare and dominant feat.&#xA;Balancing competitive strength with a passion for mentorship, Kenny continues to inspire both on and off the board, making him a highly respected figure in South African chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenneth Willenberg</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/kenneth-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/kenneth-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Sean “Kenny” Willenberg is a South African Candidate Master (CM), currently regarded as one of the country’s strongest players. A product of Steinitz Chess Club and the proud Willenberg chess-playing legacy, Kenny has built a reputation for consistent success in both national closed championships and local league competitions. Once crowned South African Under-20 Champion, he has made multiple appearances at the SA Closed Championship, firmly establishing himself as one of the nation’s leading players early in his career.&#xA;Beyond his own competitive achievements, Kenny has dedicated himself to coaching and talent development, working through programs at Curro Durbanville and Reddam House Durbanville. His impact as a coach was most prominently seen at the 2025 Top Schools competition, where his Reddam U9 team not only placed first in their division but also swept all six board prizes—a rare and dominant feat.&#xA;Balancing competitive strength with a passion for mentorship, Kenny continues to inspire both on and off the board, making him a highly respected figure in South African chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenneth Willenberg</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/kenneth-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/kenneth-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Sean “Kenny” Willenberg is a South African Candidate Master (CM), currently regarded as one of the country’s strongest players. A product of Steinitz Chess Club and the proud Willenberg chess-playing legacy, Kenny has built a reputation for consistent success in both national closed championships and local league competitions. Once crowned South African Under-20 Champion, he has made multiple appearances at the SA Closed Championship, firmly establishing himself as one of the nation’s leading players early in his career.&#xA;Beyond his own competitive achievements, Kenny has dedicated himself to coaching and talent development, working through programs at Curro Durbanville and Reddam House Durbanville. His impact as a coach was most prominently seen at the 2025 Top Schools competition, where his Reddam U9 team not only placed first in their division but also swept all six board prizes—a rare and dominant feat.&#xA;Balancing competitive strength with a passion for mentorship, Kenny continues to inspire both on and off the board, making him a highly respected figure in South African chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liam Scott</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/liam-scott/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/liam-scott/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;William Scott, known to friends and teammates as Liam, is a rising talent in the Steinitz Chess Club’s junior program. From a young age, Liam has demonstrated a natural aptitude for chess, combining sharp calculation skills with creative strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lucy Khuphwathea</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/lucy-khuphwathea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/lucy-khuphwathea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lucy Khuphwathea is a promising junior chess player from the Steinitz Chess Club and the eldest daughter of CM Paul Khuphwathea, a well respected coach hailing from Malawi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lyndon Bouah</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/lyndon-bouah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/lyndon-bouah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Lyndon Bouah is a distinguished figure in South African chess—both as a competitive veteran and as a scholar-administrator. Holding the title of Candidate Master, he has represented his nation at events including the 1992 and 1994 Chess Olympiads. In 2024, Bouah made a remarkable return to competitive play, emerging as co-champion in the Senior Section of the South African Closed Chess Championship, achieving an undefeated 8.5/11 alongside Dr. Shabier Bhawoodien.&#xA;Off the board, Dr. Bouah is a committed researcher and author, notably publishing Reflection on Chess in the Rainbow Nation, a deeply personal and cultural exploration of chess in South Africa. He also serves as the Chief Director for Sport and Recreation in the Western Cape, blending his passion for chess with leadership in public service.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lyndon Bouah</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/lyndon-bouah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/lyndon-bouah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Lyndon Bouah is a distinguished figure in South African chess—both as a competitive veteran and as a scholar-administrator. Holding the title of Candidate Master, he has represented his nation at events including the 1992 and 1994 Chess Olympiads. In 2024, Bouah made a remarkable return to competitive play, emerging as co-champion in the Senior Section of the South African Closed Chess Championship, achieving an undefeated 8.5/11 alongside Dr. Shabier Bhawoodien.&#xA;Off the board, Dr. Bouah is a committed researcher and author, notably publishing Reflection on Chess in the Rainbow Nation, a deeply personal and cultural exploration of chess in South Africa. He also serves as the Chief Director for Sport and Recreation in the Western Cape, blending his passion for chess with leadership in public service.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mark Lewis</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/mark-lewis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/mark-lewis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Lewis is a seasoned chess coach and a founding member of Cape Town’s Steinitz Chess Club, established in 1976 when four high-school students in Bonteheuwel came together to form a club named after World Champion Wilhelm Steinitz.&#xA;A respected leader in South African chess, Lewis is a former president of both the Steinitz Chess Club and the Cape Town Chess Federation (CTCF). Under his leadership, Steinitz grew into one of the strongest clubs in the country, winning national titles and nurturing top players from the Cape Flats.&#xA;In addition to his administrative and coaching roles, Lewis remains active as a competitive player, highlighted by his victory at the 2022 South African Senior Championship, scoring 7.5 points. His lifelong dedication has left a lasting mark on South African chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mark Lewis</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/mark-lewis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/mark-lewis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Lewis is a seasoned chess coach and a founding member of Cape Town’s Steinitz Chess Club, established in 1976 when four high-school students in Bonteheuwel came together to form a club named after World Champion Wilhelm Steinitz.&#xA;A respected leader in South African chess, Lewis is a former president of both the Steinitz Chess Club and the Cape Town Chess Federation (CTCF). Under his leadership, Steinitz grew into one of the strongest clubs in the country, winning national titles and nurturing top players from the Cape Flats.&#xA;In addition to his administrative and coaching roles, Lewis remains active as a competitive player, highlighted by his victory at the 2022 South African Senior Championship, scoring 7.5 points. His lifelong dedication has left a lasting mark on South African chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul Khuphwathea</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/paul-khuphwathea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/paul-khuphwathea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Paul C. Khuphwathea is a highly respected chess player and coach from Malawi, now making his mark in Cape Town, South Africa. A Candidate Master since 2016, he has represented his country with pride on the international stage, including appearances at the 2012 Chess Olympiad in Istanbul, Turkey, and again at the 42nd Olympiad in Baku, Azerbaijan, in 2016, where he faced some of the world’s strongest players.&#xA;Beyond his own competitive success, Paul has devoted himself to the growth and development of young chess talent. A licensed FIDE Developmental Instructor (2011–2025), he now coaches full time at United Herzlia Schools and the German International School of Cape Town. His dynamic teaching style and deep love for the game have inspired countless students, helping them build not only chess skills but also confidence, discipline, and critical thinking.&#xA;With his combination of international experience, coaching expertise, and passion for education, Paul continues to play a vital role in strengthening the chess culture of Cape Town and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul Khuphwathea</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/paul-khuphwathea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/paul-khuphwathea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Paul C. Khuphwathea is a highly respected chess player and coach from Malawi, now making his mark in Cape Town, South Africa. A Candidate Master since 2016, he has represented his country with pride on the international stage, including appearances at the 2012 Chess Olympiad in Istanbul, Turkey, and again at the 42nd Olympiad in Baku, Azerbaijan, in 2016, where he faced some of the world’s strongest players.&#xA;Beyond his own competitive success, Paul has devoted himself to the growth and development of young chess talent. A licensed FIDE Developmental Instructor (2011–2025), he now coaches full time at United Herzlia Schools and the German International School of Cape Town. His dynamic teaching style and deep love for the game have inspired countless students, helping them build not only chess skills but also confidence, discipline, and critical thinking.&#xA;With his combination of international experience, coaching expertise, and passion for education, Paul continues to play a vital role in strengthening the chess culture of Cape Town and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul Vorster</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/paul-vorster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/paul-vorster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Paul Vorster is a talented young chess player and active participant at individual and team competitions.&#xA;In February 2025, Paul achieved a notable second-place finish in the Advanced Section of the Cape of Good Hope Open 2025, a prestigious tournament in the Western Cape. He also represented his school, Stellenberg High School, in the Cape Town Metro Schools Chess Team, highlighting his active involvement in regional chess activities.&#xA;Paul&amp;rsquo;s dedication to chess is further evident from his inclusion in the Western Province U16 Open Trials in 2022, indicating his early promise and commitment to the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phillip Tjale</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/phillip-tjale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/phillip-tjale/</guid>
      <description>Phillipmaite Tjale learned how to play chess on a home-made set, much like the great Mikhail Botvinnik. This unique start sparked a deep appreciation for the Soviet-era chess players and a love for dynamic, attacking styles, with solid positional foundations. While his passion lies in aggressive play, his style is more a testament to the fundamentals: a solid, balanced approach that focuses on defensive soundness and capitalizing on his opponent&amp;rsquo;s errors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pierre Goosen</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/pierre-goosen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/pierre-goosen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pierre Goosen is a South African chess player who in recent years relocated to Cape Town and became a valued member of the Steinitz Chess Club. His decision to join Steinitz came naturally: when he mentioned his move to a colleague, he was told without hesitation that Steinitz is the best club in the country — advice he gladly took to heart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At &lt;strong&gt;Steinitz Chess Club&lt;/strong&gt;, we’re not just about chess — we’re about people. That means we respect your privacy and take care to protect any personal information you share with us. This policy explains, in plain language, what we collect, why we collect it, and how you stay in control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ready to build your next project with Hugo?</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reegan Palmer</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/reegan-palmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/reegan-palmer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reegan Palmer is a rising chess star from Cape Town, South Africa, celebrated for his sharp tactical acumen and strategic depth. In 2025, he secured a remarkable 7 points out of 9 in the South African Junior Closed Chess Championship (U18 Open), sharing the top spot with Lin Chenyi and earning a FIDE rating performance of 1791 . This performance underscores his prowess in the national chess arena.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Richard Korebrits</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/richard-korebrits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/richard-korebrits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Richard Korebrits has been a long-standing member of Steinitz and an avid participant in individual as well as team-based tournaments. He first showed his fighting spirit during a pivitol team match at the Eden Championship in the garden route. Since then he has gained strength consistently and can always be counted upon to represent his club when it matters most.&#xA;On a personal note, he does not have children but does have pets. One of them is a Siamese cat named Chess, after Alexander Alekhine&amp;rsquo;s famous cat by the same name.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland Willenberg </title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/roland-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/roland-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Roland Willenberg is a veteran South African chess coach and one of the founding members of Steinitz. As a trailblazer in coaching, he was recognized as Cape Town’s first professional chess coach.&#xA;Roland is also known as the father and early mentor of his sons, Kenny and Craig, both former junior South African champions. His contributions to South African chess—through community building, mentorship, and fostering talent—cement his reputation as a key figure in nurturing chess culture on the Cape Flats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roland Willenberg </title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/roland-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/roland-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Roland Willenberg is a veteran South African chess coach and one of the founding members of Steinitz. As a trailblazer in coaching, he was recognized as Cape Town’s first professional chess coach.&#xA;Roland is also known as the father and early mentor of his sons, Kenny and Craig, both former junior South African champions. His contributions to South African chess—through community building, mentorship, and fostering talent—cement his reputation as a key figure in nurturing chess culture on the Cape Flats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romayo Page</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/romayo-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/romayo-page/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Romayo Page’s journey in chess is a testament to dedication, mentorship, and community spirit. From the early days of competing with Boland A and B teams during the 1990s—sharing the stage with renowned players like Deon Pick and Kenny Solomon—Romayo’s love for the game was evident. Guided by the late Mr. Brown, a multifaceted mentor whose talents spanned authorship, songwriting, and chess, Romayo’s passion for the sport grew deeper with each passing year.&#xA;As a leader, Romayo left a lasting mark on Western Cape Chess. Serving as Western Province Manager for Top Schools from 2009 to 2015, Romayo orchestrated a golden era for The Settlers High School Chess teams, who remained unbeaten for nine consecutive years—a feat made possible by the unwavering commitment of Steinitz coaches and a thriving school spirit.&#xA;Romayo’s connection to the Willenberg family during his teaching tenure at The Settlers High School proved pivotal. This bond naturally led Romayo to join Steinitz Chess Club, where the sense of family and shared ambition continued to flourish.&#xA;Throughout his career, Romayo Page has not only achieved personal success on the chessboard but has also inspired a generation of young players and fostered a vibrant chess community—demonstrating that, in chess as in life, it takes a village to nurture greatness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romayo Page</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/romayo-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/romayo-page/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Romayo Page’s journey in chess is a testament to dedication, mentorship, and community spirit. From the early days of competing with Boland A and B teams during the 1990s—sharing the stage with renowned players like Deon Pick and Kenny Solomon—Romayo’s love for the game was evident. Guided by the late Mr. Brown, a multifaceted mentor whose talents spanned authorship, songwriting, and chess, Romayo’s passion for the sport grew deeper with each passing year.&#xA;As a leader, Romayo left a lasting mark on Western Cape Chess. Serving as Western Province Manager for Top Schools from 2009 to 2015, Romayo orchestrated a golden era for The Settlers High School Chess teams, who remained unbeaten for nine consecutive years—a feat made possible by the unwavering commitment of Steinitz coaches and a thriving school spirit.&#xA;Romayo’s connection to the Willenberg family during his teaching tenure at The Settlers High School proved pivotal. This bond naturally led Romayo to join Steinitz Chess Club, where the sense of family and shared ambition continued to flourish.&#xA;Throughout his career, Romayo Page has not only achieved personal success on the chessboard but has also inspired a generation of young players and fostered a vibrant chess community—demonstrating that, in chess as in life, it takes a village to nurture greatness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shaqeel Petersen-Bizaare</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/shaqeel-petersen-bizaare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/shaqeel-petersen-bizaare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shaqeel has been an active member of the Insight Chess Academy, run by Steinitz president Andrew Talmarkes. He represented the academy in the Under-17 Mixed category, where his team secured 3rd place . Additionally, he was recognized for his excellence in chess during his Grade 10 year at Protea Heights Academy, achieving 1st place in the school&amp;rsquo;s chess rankings. Recently he guided his school team to a podium finish at the Top Schools competition.&#xA;Shaqeel&amp;rsquo;s involvement in both individual and team events reflects his dedication to the game and his potential for future growth in the chess community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shaun Willenberg </title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/shaun-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/shaun-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shaun Willenberg is a founding member of the Steinitz Chess Club in Cape Town, established in 1976. The club was formed by four high-school students in the Kalksteensfontein area of Bonteheuwel, who named it after the first recognised chess world champion, Austrian Wilhelm Steinitz.&#xA;Shaun has been actively involved in the club&amp;rsquo;s activities over the years. In the 2020 Steinitz Chess Festival, he was among the top performers, finishing on tiebreak in a five-way tie for first place.&#xA;Shaun&amp;rsquo;s contributions have been instrumental in the club&amp;rsquo;s development and success, reflecting his dedication to promoting chess in the Cape Flats community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shaun Willenberg </title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/shaun-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/shaun-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shaun Willenberg is a founding member of the Steinitz Chess Club in Cape Town, established in 1976. The club was formed by four high-school students in the Kalksteensfontein area of Bonteheuwel, who named it after the first recognised chess world champion, Austrian Wilhelm Steinitz.&#xA;Shaun has been actively involved in the club&amp;rsquo;s activities over the years. In the 2020 Steinitz Chess Festival, he was among the top performers, finishing on tiebreak in a five-way tie for first place.&#xA;Shaun&amp;rsquo;s contributions have been instrumental in the club&amp;rsquo;s development and success, reflecting his dedication to promoting chess in the Cape Flats community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shaurya Singh</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/shaurya-singh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/shaurya-singh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shaurya Singh is a rising talent in South African chess and a dedicated member of the Steinitz Chess Club in Cape Town. Representing the Western Cape, he has delivered consistently strong performances at both regional and national level events.&#xA;In 2023, he achieved a notable victory in the Intermediate section of the Western Cape Women’s Championship in Langebaan, while still in primary school, signaling his early promise. The same year, he went on to win the Western Cape Individual School Chess Tournament.&#xA;Shaurya has since continued to distinguish himself in national competitions. At the 2025 South African Junior Closed Chess Championship (U14 Open), he scored 7 points out of 9, finishing in 3rd place. He has also competed in other high-level events such as the Moja Chess Extravaganza and the Cape Town Masters, further cementing his reputation as one of the Western Cape’s strongest junior players.&#xA;Beyond results, Shaurya is an active and enthusiastic participant in the local chess scene. His dedication to continuous improvement and his growing track record of tournament success make him one of the promising young players to watch in South African chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sophia Hagen</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/sophia-hagen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/sophia-hagen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sophia Hagen is an emerging chess talent from Cape Town, South Africa, born in 2012. As of September 2025, she holds a FIDE ID of 14378558, reflecting her affiliation with the South African Chess Federation.&#xA;International Chess Federation (FIDE)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triston Willenberg</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/triston-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/triston-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Triston Willenberg is a South African chess player in his early twenties, representing the Steinitz Chess Club. A steady presence on the competitive circuit, he is known for his resilience and consistency in play, maintaining steady progress in his results over recent years. He tends to play solidly, often choosing classical time controls and engaging in well-balanced games, showing patience and composure against a wide range of opponents. As part of the younger generation of South African players, Triston continues to build his experience and reputation, contributing to both his club and the broader chess community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waynika Caeser </title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/waynika-caeser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/members/waynika-caeser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Waynika Caeser discovered chess just three years ago and has quickly established herself as a rising talent in the Western Cape schools circuit. Her competitive journey began at the District East Trials, where she made an immediate impression by finishing 3rd in the combined U17 and U19 girls’ section.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What people Are Saying About Steinitz Chess Club</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
