<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steinitzians in action! on Steinitz Chess Club</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Steinitzians in action! on Steinitz Chess Club</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/gallery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025 CTCF Club League</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/2025_ctcf-club-league/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/2025_ctcf-club-league/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2025 CTCF Club League is Cape Town’s premier team chess competition, bringing together the region’s strongest clubs in an 11-round tournament played over three months. The league showcases both established masters and rising talents, fostering competitive spirit and community among local players. With the season still underway, every round remains crucial as teams battle for top honors and bragging rights in one of South Africa’s most prestigious club events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Hermanus Chess Club Open</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/2025_hermanus-chess-club-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/2025_hermanus-chess-club-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hermanus Chess Club hosted it&amp;rsquo;s annual open on a rainy April day. However, multiple Steinitz players shone brightly, bringing home medals and trophies in all divisions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Steinitz Festival</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/2024_steinitz-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/2024_steinitz-festival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 47th anniversary Steinitz Chess Festival took place at Fairbairn College, Goodwood. 250 players participated with various Junior age groups, rapid sections, Fide rated sections. Players came from as far afield as Namibia, KZN and Mossel Bay, Overberg.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Club Championship</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/2024-04-13_steinitz-club-championship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/2024-04-13_steinitz-club-championship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2024 Annual Steinitz Chess Club Championship took place in Cape Town on Saturday, April 13th, 2024. The event featured six rounds played at a rapid time control of 20 minutes plus a 5-second increment per move. Bringing together a strong field of club members, the championship provided an exciting day of competitive chess, highlighting both seasoned players and rising stars within the Steinitz community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 SA Senior Closed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/2024_sa-senior-closed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/2024_sa-senior-closed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2024 SA Senior Closed at the iconic Newlands venue was a fiercely contested and well-organized event, ending with Dr Lyndon Bouah and FM Shabier Bhawoodien sharing the senior title in a fitting display of competitive balance and sporting tradition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 CTCF Club League</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/2022_ctcf-club-league/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/2022_ctcf-club-league/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to our Steinitz A-team for winning the Premier Division of the 2022 Chess WP Club League Championship! We also congratulate Kraaifontein (winners of B Division), Capablanca (winners of C Division) and Delft (winners of D Division).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2014 AfriClub Champs</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/2014_african-club-championship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/2014_african-club-championship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In March 2014, Cape Town proudly hosted the prestigious African Club Chess Championship at the Sun Hotel. The event brought together top club teams from across the continent, showcasing Africa’s finest chess talent in a spirit of competition and camaraderie. Players battled over the boards in a festival of strategy and skill, while the Mother City provided a fitting backdrop with its vibrant culture and iconic scenery. The tournament not only highlighted the growing strength of African chess but also reinforced Cape Town’s reputation as a hub for international sporting events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
