<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authors on Steinitz Chess Club - With Unity to Prosperity</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/</link><description>Recent content in Authors on Steinitz Chess Club - With Unity to Prosperity</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kenneth Willenberg</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/kenneth-willenberg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/kenneth-willenberg/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Sean “Kenny” Willenberg is a South African Candidate Master (CM), currently regarded as one of the country’s strongest players. A product of Steinitz Chess Club and the proud Willenberg chess-playing legacy, Kenny has built a reputation for consistent success in both national closed championships and local league competitions. Once crowned South African Under-20 Champion, he has made multiple appearances at the SA Closed Championship, firmly establishing himself as one of the nation’s leading players early in his career.
Beyond his own competitive achievements, Kenny has dedicated himself to coaching and talent development, working through programs at Curro Durbanville and Reddam House Durbanville. He was the originator of the Curro Cup, South Africa’s first online schools chess tournament, which has since grown into a landmark event on the scholastic calendar. His impact as a coach was most prominently seen at the 2025 Top Schools competition, where his Reddam U9 team not only placed first in their division but also swept all six board prizes—a rare and dominant feat.
Balancing competitive strength with a passion for mentorship, Kenny continues to inspire both on and off the board, making him a highly respected figure in South African chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lyndon Bouah</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/lyndon-bouah/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/authors/lyndon-bouah/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Lyndon Bouah is a distinguished figure in South African chess—both as a competitive veteran and as a scholar-administrator. Holding the title of Candidate Master, he has represented his nation at events including the 1992 and 1994 Chess Olympiads. In 2024, Bouah made a remarkable return to competitive play, emerging as co-champion in the Senior Section of the South African Closed Chess Championship, achieving an undefeated 8.5/11 alongside Dr. Shabier Bhawoodien.
Off the board, Dr. Bouah is a committed researcher and author, notably publishing Reflection on Chess in the Rainbow Nation, a deeply personal and cultural exploration of chess in South Africa. He also serves as the Chief Director for Sport and Recreation in the Western Cape, blending his passion for chess with leadership in public service.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>