<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Executive Committee on Steinitz Chess Club - With Unity to Prosperity</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/</link><description>Recent content in Executive Committee on Steinitz Chess Club - With Unity to Prosperity</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Andrew Talmarkes</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/andrew-talmarkes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/andrew-talmarkes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew Talmarkes is an accomplished chess coach, FIDE-licensed arbiter, and long-time leader within Cape Town’s Steinitz Chess Club. He is the Director of the Insight Chess Academy, providing specialized individual and group coaching—including tailored sessions for clients with ADHD or focus challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Clinton Solomon</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/clinton-solomon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/clinton-solomon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Clinton Solomon is a passionate chess organizer, mentor, and advocate for youth chess in Cape Town. As the Youth Director of Steinitz Chess Club, he works tirelessly to create opportunities for young players, providing access to quality coaching, structured tournaments, and a supportive community. Since 2019, Clinton has traveled extensively across South Africa with his son, Izaiah Solomon—one of the region’s most promising young chess talents—attending both Federation and school chess tournaments. These experiences have given him a deep understanding of the needs and challenges facing youth chess players.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Colin Webber</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/colin-webber/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/colin-webber/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Colin Webber is an active member of the Cape Town chess community, balancing his own journey as an “adult improver” with his passion for supporting the game. A former chess parent—his son Ethan no longer plays competitively—Colin has stayed deeply connected to the sport through both playing and service. He currently serves as the Technical Officer and Webmaster of Steinitz Chess Club, where he helps manage the club’s digital presence and supports its ongoing growth. Alongside his technical contributions, Colin enjoys encouraging and mentoring young players, drawing on his experiences as both a parent and competitor. His enthusiasm for lifelong learning and his commitment to fostering talent make him a valuable part of the Steinitz family.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Declan Platen</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/declan-platen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/declan-platen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Declan Platen is a respected player, coach, and leader within the Steinitz Chess Club, where he currently serves as Club Captain. Known for his steady play and deep understanding of the game, Declan has represented Steinitz in league competitions and other events, contributing both on and off the board. As a coach, he is dedicated to nurturing young talent, sharing his knowledge and experience to help players sharpen their skills and build confidence. His approachable teaching style and passion for chess make him a role model for many up-and-coming players in the Western Cape. In his role as Club Captain, Declan fosters team spirit and ensures that Steinitz continues its proud tradition of excellence and camaraderie. Balancing competitive play with mentorship, he exemplifies the values of leadership, sportsmanship, and commitment to the growth of chess in his community.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jody Roman</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/jody-roman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/jody-roman/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Jody Roman has always had a passion for chess. Through a chance interaction with one of Steinitz’s long-standing members, he was reintroduced to the game and welcomed into the close-knit Steinitz family. As a social player and adult improver, Jody has been eager to contribute—taking on the role of Team Captain for various development teams, competing more actively in local tournaments, and even stepping into an ExCo position at the club.
Reflecting on his journey, Jody lives by the words of Wilhelm Steinitz: “Chess is not for timid souls.” The game brings both highs and lows, but for him, it is about taking the bull by the horns and enjoying the ride.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mark Lewis</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/mark-lewis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/mark-lewis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Lewis is a seasoned chess coach and a founding member of Cape Town’s Steinitz Chess Club, established in 1976 when four high-school students in Bonteheuwel came together to form a club named after World Champion Wilhelm Steinitz.
A respected leader in South African chess, Lewis is a former president of both the Steinitz Chess Club and the Cape Town Chess Federation (CTCF). Under his leadership, Steinitz grew into one of the strongest clubs in the country, winning national titles and nurturing top players from the Cape Flats.
In addition to his administrative and coaching roles, Lewis remains active as a competitive player, highlighted by his victory at the 2022 South African Senior Championship, scoring 7.5 points. His lifelong dedication has left a lasting mark on South African chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Roland Willenberg</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/roland-willenberg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/roland-willenberg/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Roland Willenberg is a veteran South African chess coach and one of the founding members of Steinitz. As a trailblazer in coaching, he was recognized as Cape Town’s first professional chess coach.
Roland is also known as the father and early mentor of his sons, Kenny and Craig, both former junior South African champions. His contributions to South African chess—through community building, mentorship, and fostering talent—cement his reputation as a key figure in nurturing chess culture on the Cape Flats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Romayo Page</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/romayo-page/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/romayo-page/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Romayo Page’s journey in chess is a testament to dedication, mentorship, and community spirit. From the early days of competing with Boland A and B teams during the 1990s—sharing the stage with renowned players like Deon Pick and Kenny Solomon—Romayo’s love for the game was evident. Guided by the late Mr. Brown, a multifaceted mentor whose talents spanned authorship, songwriting, and chess, Romayo’s passion for the sport grew deeper with each passing year.
As a leader, Romayo left a lasting mark on Western Cape Chess. Serving as Western Province Manager for Top Schools from 2009 to 2015, Romayo orchestrated a golden era for The Settlers High School Chess teams, who remained unbeaten for nine consecutive years—a feat made possible by the unwavering commitment of Steinitz coaches and a thriving school spirit.
Romayo’s connection to the Willenberg family during his teaching tenure at The Settlers High School proved pivotal. This bond naturally led Romayo to join Steinitz Chess Club, where the sense of family and shared ambition continued to flourish.
Throughout his career, Romayo Page has not only achieved personal success on the chessboard but has also inspired a generation of young players and fostered a vibrant chess community—demonstrating that, in chess as in life, it takes a village to nurture greatness.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Shaun Willenberg</title><link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/shaun-willenberg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/leaders/shaun-willenberg/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Shaun Willenberg is a founding member of the Steinitz Chess Club in Cape Town, established in 1976. The club was formed by four high-school students in the Kalksteensfontein area of Bonteheuwel, who named it after the first recognised chess world champion, Austrian Wilhelm Steinitz.
Shaun has been actively involved in the club&amp;rsquo;s activities over the years. In the 2020 Steinitz Chess Festival, he was among the top performers, finishing on tiebreak in a five-way tie for first place.
Shaun&amp;rsquo;s contributions have been instrumental in the club&amp;rsquo;s development and success, reflecting his dedication to promoting chess in the Cape Flats community.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>