<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coaches on Steinitz Chess Club - With Unity to Prosperity</title>
    <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coaches on Steinitz Chess Club - With Unity to Prosperity</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Talmarkes </title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/andrew-talmarkes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/andrew-talmarkes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew Talmarkes is an accomplished chess coach, FIDE-licensed arbiter, and long-time leader within Cape Town’s Steinitz Chess Club. He is the Director of the Insight Chess Academy, providing specialized individual and group coaching—including tailored sessions for clients with ADHD or focus challenges.&#xA;A pillar in chess administration, he has served in numerous key roles: tournament director, deputy chief arbiter at the 2024 Cape Town Masters Challenge, and fixture within the CHESSA arbiter program as well as the Western Province youth coaching scene.&#xA;Awarded the Community Builder Award in 2013 for his work on Mitchell’s Plain Chess Development and Library Project, Talmarkes continues to shape youth and community chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethan Samuels</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/ethan-samuels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/ethan-samuels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ethan Samuels is an accomplished young adult chess player and coach from Cape Town, South Africa. Known for his sharp tactical awareness and steady positional play, he has developed a strong reputation both over the board and as a mentor to aspiring players. Ethan has represented his club and province in numerous competitions, consistently achieving notable results and establishing himself as one of the promising young figures in the South African chess scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenneth Willenberg</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/kenneth-willenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/kenneth-willenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Sean “Kenny” Willenberg is a South African Candidate Master (CM), currently regarded as one of the country’s strongest players. A product of Steinitz Chess Club and the proud Willenberg chess-playing legacy, Kenny has built a reputation for consistent success in both national closed championships and local league competitions. Once crowned South African Under-20 Champion, he has made multiple appearances at the SA Closed Championship, firmly establishing himself as one of the nation’s leading players early in his career.&#xA;Beyond his own competitive achievements, Kenny has dedicated himself to coaching and talent development, working through programs at Curro Durbanville and Reddam House Durbanville. He was the originator of the Curro Cup, South Africa’s first online schools chess tournament, which has since grown into a landmark event on the scholastic calendar. His impact as a coach was most prominently seen at the 2025 Top Schools competition, where his Reddam U9 team not only placed first in their division but also swept all six board prizes—a rare and dominant feat.&#xA;Balancing competitive strength with a passion for mentorship, Kenny continues to inspire both on and off the board, making him a highly respected figure in South African chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul Khuphwathea</title>
      <link>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/paul-khuphwathea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://test.steinitzchessclub.co.za/coaches/paul-khuphwathea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Paul C. Khuphwathea is a highly respected chess player and coach from Malawi, now making his mark in Cape Town, South Africa. A Candidate Master since 2016, he has represented his country with pride on the international stage, including appearances at the 2012 Chess Olympiad in Istanbul, Turkey, and again at the 42nd Olympiad in Baku, Azerbaijan, in 2016, where he faced some of the world’s strongest players.&#xA;Beyond his own competitive success, Paul has devoted himself to the growth and development of young chess talent. A licensed FIDE Developmental Instructor (2011–2025), he now coaches full time at United Herzlia Schools and the German International School of Cape Town. His dynamic teaching style and deep love for the game have inspired countless students, helping them build not only chess skills but also confidence, discipline, and critical thinking.&#xA;With his combination of international experience, coaching expertise, and passion for education, Paul continues to play a vital role in strengthening the chess culture of Cape Town and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
